export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA1998 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following is common to all forms of literature?",
A: "language",
B: "chorus",
C: "action",
D: "narrator",
answer: "A. language",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The three major forms of literature are",
A: "tragedy, comedy, tragi-comedy",
B: "poetry, drama, folktales",
C: "drama, lyric, prose friction",
D: "poetry, drama, prose",
answer: "D. poetry, drama, prose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Beauty in poetry depends mainly on",
A: "expression and rhythm",
B: "length and theme",
C: "vowels and consonants",
D: "mood and verse form",
answer: "A. expression and rhythm",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The predominant figure of speech in the above extract is",
A: "oxymoron",
B: "metaphor",
C: "simile",
D: "personification",
answer: "D. personification",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The subject matter of the above extract is",
A: "earthquake",
B: "house movement",
C: "sea waves",
D: "storm",
answer: "A. earthquake",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The image depicted in the extract is one of",
A: "destruction",
B: "merriment",
C: "happiness",
D: "admiration",
answer: "A. destruction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Pick the odd item from the list below",
A: "Night Rain",
B: "Things Fall Apart",
C: "Stanley Meets Mutesa",
D: "Nightfall in Soweto",
answer: "B. Things Fall Apart (This is a novel, while the others are titles of poems)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The poetic device used in the above extract is",
A: "assonance",
B: "alliteration",
C: "metaphor",
D: "metonymy",
answer: "C. metaphor",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. A poem written or rendered in praise of a person or thing is called",
A: "a lyric",
B: "anode",
C: "an elegy",
D: "a panegyric",
answer: "D. a panegyric",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The basic elements of drama are",
A: "character, plot, episode",
B: "dialogue, chorus, plot",
C: "character, action, setting",
D: "character, monologue, plot",
answer: "C. character, action, setting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The choice of appropriate words to convey the thoughts of an author is called",
A: "idiomatic language",
B: "setting",
C: "figure of speech",
D: "diction",
answer: "D. diction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The state of mind of a poet can be described as",
A: "style",
B: "mood",
C: "setting",
D: "theme",
answer: "B. mood",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following is a likely source of traditional oral poetry?",
A: "theatre",
B: "fiction",
C: "books",
D: "songs",
answer: "D. songs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. An African author who has written plays, poems and prose is",
A: "Wole Soyinka",
B: "Zaynab Alkali",
C: "Chinua Achebe",
D: "Flora Nwapa",
answer: "A. Wole Soyinka",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In a novel, the antagonist is",
A: "a fully developed character",
B: "a flat character",
C: "the main female character",
D: "the arch rival of the hero",
answer: "D. the arch rival of the hero",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The figure of speech underlined in line I is",
A: "assonance",
B: "consonance",
C: "onomatopoeia",
D: "alliteration",
answer: "C. onomatopoeia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The underlined expression in line 3 is",
A: "litotes",
B: "personification",
C: "hyperbole",
D: "synecdoche",
answer: "B. personification",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In poetry, rhythm is created by the regular pattern of",
A: "vowel and consonants",
B: "long and short words",
C: "stressed and unstressed syllables",
D: "stressed syllables and rhythms",
answer: "C. stressed and unstressed syllables",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is an African poet?",
A: "Dennis Brutus",
B: "Williams Wordsworth",
C: "Robert Frost",
D: "W.B.Yeast",
answer: "A. Dennis Brutus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A play that is full of exaggerated ridicule and laughter is called",
A: "farce e",
B: "comedy",
C: "tragi-comedy",
D: "masque",
answer: "A. farce",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In a play, a long speech by a single character in the presence of other characters is called",
A: "soliloquy",
B: "monologue",
C: "aside",
D: "prologue",
answer: "B. monologue",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Pick the odd item from the list below",
A: "tragedy",
B: "comedy",
C: "epilogue",
D: "tragi-comedy",
answer: "C. epilogue (Epilogue is a concluding section at the end of a literary work, while the others are types of plays)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. A group of actors in a play is called",
A: "characters",
B: "cas",
C: "chorus",
D: "prompters",
answer: "C. chorus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A novel is usually written in",
A: "prose",
B: "verde",
C: "scenes",
D: "stanzas",
answer: "A. prose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. What distinguishes a novel from a play is",
A: "character",
B: "setting",
C: "narration",
D: "heme",
answer: "C. narration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following best describes literature? It",
A: "tells the story of great men and women.",
B: "is a reflection of man’s life in society.",
C: "is a record of past events.",
D: "describes what never happened, and cannot happen.",
answer: "B. is a reflection of man’s life in society.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The literary device in the statement Students are to come to class with their Shakespeare is called",
A: "metonymy",
B: "litotes",
C: "synecdoche",
D: "personification",
answer: "C. synecdoche (Shakespeare represents all literature)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The first person narrator is usually",
A: "the protagonist",
B: "a villain in the novel",
C: "the antagonist",
D: "a character in the novel",
answer: "A. the protagonist",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following is closest to the form of the novel?",
A: "the short story",
B: "fable",
C: "tale",
D: "epic",
answer: "A. the short story",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. “The people’s voices rutted like pigs in the mud” is an example of",
A: "Simile",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Personification",
D: "Metonymy",
answer: "C. Personification (Giving the people's voices the human action of 'rutting')",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The rhyme scheme is",
A: "abba",
B: "ahab",
C: "aabb",
D: "bbaa",
answer: "A. abba",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. This kind of rhyme scheme is known as a",
A: "Alternate",
B: "Irregular",
C: "Free verse",
D: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
answer: "A. Alternate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A poem of four lines is known as a",
A: "Sonnet",
B: "Couplet",
C: "Sestet",
D: "Quatrain",
answer: "D. Quatrain",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A poem of 14 lines is known as a",
A: "Quatrain",
B: "Octave",
C: "Sestet",
D: "Sonnet",
answer: "D. Sonnet",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Pick the odd item from the list",
A: "Prose",
B: "Poetry",
C: "Drama",
D: "Tragedy",
answer: "A. Prose (The others are literary genres)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. A play on words is",
A: "Innuendo",
B: "Humor",
C: "Pun",
D: "Jest",
answer: "C. Pun",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A play is fully realized when it is",
A: "Studied",
B: "Memorized",
C: "Acted",
D: "Read",
answer: "C. Acted",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. An epitaph is",
A: "Poem of lamentation",
B: "A poem of fourteen lines",
C: "An inscription on a tomb",
D: "The life history of an author",
answer: "C. An inscription on a tomb",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The essential function of a tragedy is to make people",
A: "Laugh at mankind",
B: "Think and feel more deeply",
C: "Think and laugh",
D: "Know their enemies",
answer: "B. Think and feel more deeply",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Mime is the art of acting that involves the use of",
A: "Songs only",
B: "Speeches only",
C: "Gestures only",
D: "Dances only",
answer: "C. Gestures only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A short witty statement is called an",
A: "Epigram",
B: "Anecdote",
C: "Epistle",
D: "Analog",
answer: "A. Epigram",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Penny wise; pound foolish is an example of",
A: "Metonymy",
B: "Hyperbole",
C: "Metaphor",
D: "Paradox",
answer: "D. Paradox",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. All fingers are not equal is an example",
A: "Meiosis",
B: "Oxymoron",
C: "Hyperbole",
D: "Synecdoche",
answer: "A. Meiosis (Understatement)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Any expression which creates a mental picture is known as",
A: "Paradox",
B: "Exaggeration",
C: "Imagery",
D: "Symbolism",
answer: "C. Imagery",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The predominant sound device in the extract is",
A: "Assonance",
B: "Consonance",
C: "Onomatopoeia",
D: "Alliteration",
answer: "C. Onomatopoeia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The underlined words in lines 1 and 3 are example of",
A: "External rhyme",
B: "Internal rhyme",
C: "End rhyme",
D: "Alternate rhyme",
answer: "B. Internal rhyme ('humming' and 'humming')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The omniscient narrator",
A: "Uses flashback",
B: "Knows all about characters and events",
C: "Makes reference to future incidents",
D: "Knows all about author",
answer: "B. Knows all about characters and events",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The main female character in a play is called",
A: "Hero",
B: "Heroine",
C: "Clown",
D: "Antagonist",
answer: "B. Heroine",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The character that opposes the hero in a novel is called the",
A: "Protagonist",
B: "Antagonist",
C: "Villain",
D: "Clown",
answer: "C. Villain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Pick the odd item from the list",
A: "Sentence",
B: "Paragraph",
C: "Expression",
D: "Fiction",
answer: "A. Sentence (The others are literary forms)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. The setting of this extract is the",
A: "Field",
B: "Stream",
C: "Farm",
D: "Mountain",
answer: "D. Mountain",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. The mood of the narrator is one of",
A: "Shock",
B: "Indifference",
C: "Happiness",
D: "Kindness",
answer: "A. Shock",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. The narrator’s companion has just",
A: "Died",
B: "Arrived",
C: "Relaxed",
D: "Collapsed",
answer: "A. Died",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. The extract is an example of a",
A: "Narrative prose",
B: "Descriptive prose",
C: "imaginative prose",
D: "Expository prose",
answer: "A. Narrative prose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. The underlined expression is an example of",
A: "Hyperbole",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Simile",
D: "Personification",
answer: "C. Simile ('stole across the land' - comparing the stream's movement to stealing)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. The figure of speech used in the first sentence is",
A: "personification",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Simile",
D: "Metonymy",
answer: "B. Metaphor ('blossomed like spring flowers' - comparing her love to flowers)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. In England, she had loved her husband, in Africa, she",
A: "Resented him",
B: "Accepted him",
C: "Enjoyed her honeymoon",
D: "Encouraged him",
answer: "A. Resented him",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. From that day her world collapsed shows that the woman is",
A: "Better off",
B: "Wise",
C: "Afraid",
D: "Unhappy",
answer: "D. Unhappy",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. What made the woman’s world collapse is",
A: "Falling in love with her husband in winter",
B: "Cutting short their honey moon",
C: "Travelling aboard a ship",
D: "Their movement to Africa",
answer: "D. Their movement to Africa",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. From the last sentence, it is obvious that the couple",
A: "Is happy",
B: "Is lonely",
C: "Is childless",
D: "Has a child",
answer: "C. Is childless",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question61",
question:  "61. The poem is an example of",
A: "A lyric",
B: "A dirge",
C: "An ode",
D: "An epic",
answer: "A. A lyric (A lyric poem expresses personal emotions)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question62",
question:  "62. The predominant literary device used in the extract is",
A: "Hyperbole",
B: "Epigrams",
C: "Oxymoron",
D: "Apostrophe",
answer: "B. Metaphor (Comparing love to milk, butter, and a bird's egg)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question63",
question:  "63. The feeling of the poet is one of",
A: "Anxiety",
B: "Gaiety",
C: "Sadness",
D: "Frustration",
answer: "B. Gaiety",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question64",
question:  "64. The underlined expression contains a",
A: "Simile",
B: "Metaphor",
C: "Personification",
D: "Litote65. The poem is a blank verse because",
answer: "B. Metaphor ('You are the cattle-bird's egg')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question65",
question:  "65. *******************************",
A: "There is no rhyme",
B: "There is rhyme",
C: "The rhyme is alternate",
D: "It contains couplets",
answer: "A. There is no rhyme",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question66",
question:  "66. The rhyme scheme of the above extract is",
A: "Alternate",
B: "Irregular",
C: "Free verse",
D: "Couplet",
answer: "A. Alternate (abab)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question67",
question:  "67. The literary device used in line 1 is an example of",
A: "Climax",
B: "Apostrophe",
C: "Metonymy",
D: "Euphemism",
answer: "B. Apostrophe (Addressing 'stealing time')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question68",
question:  "68. The literary device in lines 3 and 4 of stanza I is",
A: "Paradox",
B: "Antithesis",
C: "Apostrophe",
D: "Rhetorical question",
answer: "B. Antithesis ('Old age is wise... Old age hath known')",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question69",
question:  "69. The predominant figure of speech in stanza II is",
A: "Consonance",
B: "Alliteration",
C: "Personification",
D: "Epigram",
answer: "C. Personification ('Old age hath known')",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question70",
question:  "70. The mood of the poet is that of",
A: "Carelessness",
B: "Happiness",
C: "Gaiety",
D: "Helplessness",
answer: "D. Helplessness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]